## Jay Lim

Jaylim106@gmail.com ❖ 310-617-4644 ❖ San Diego, CA ❖ jaylim.net ❖ Github

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY: Talented full-stack/backend software engineer with over 3 years of proven leadership experience as a team tech lead, supporting a team of 6 individuals. Consistently and timely delivers business value on projects.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Signifyd Jan 2024 - Present

Staff Software Engineer, Team Tech Lead

Remote

- Delivered a presentation to Signifyd's engineering staff on decisioning architecture at the company offsite.
- Trained an 8-person team in Belfast on Decision Center codebase, expediting their onboarding process.
- Re-architected microservice infrastructure, reducing operations/infrastructure cost by \$1000/month.
- Reduced merchant onboarding time by 83% (6 days  $\rightarrow$  1 day) and eliminated the need for support tickets.
- Led upgrade of backend microservices to Java 21, enabling adoption of latest third-party dependencies.

Signifyd Jan 2022 - Jan 2024

Senior Software Engineer, Team Tech Lead

Remote

- Improved reliability of Decision Center simulations by eliminating a single point of failure, reducing failed runs from ~2 per week to zero. Enhanced performance by parallelizing task execution across multiple pods.
- Led effort to eliminate 5xx errors across services, mitigating 70% of exceptions from Cassandra and 95% from AWS ELB. Resolved intermittent MySQL issues caused by page cleaner activity.
- Developed **code generation** for **machine learning feature descriptions**, eliminating human error and improving organization-wide efficiency. Widely adopted by engineers and data scientists as a critical tool.

Signifyd Oct 2020 – Dec 2021

Software Engineer

Remote

- Investigated root cause of a poorly performing MYSQL query and reduced p99 latency from 1.2 sec to 50 ms.
- Led tech debt project to refactor HTTP authorization/authentication which unblocked upgrading version of Play! framework to v2.7.9.
- Consistently participated in engineering on-call rotations, adeptly resolving customer-facing incidents promptly
  and effectively, even during weekends and off-hours.

HaloSentient Sept 2018 – Aug 2020

Fullstack Developer

Remote

- Implemented mobile friendly ecommerce marketplace website using React/Redux with hooks, Node.js, Typescript, Firebase, and Stripe as the payment processor.
- Designed and developed full stack web app using React, MongoDB and Socket.io for real-time UI updates.
- Audited (QA) for interview-based web (**Angular/Node.js**) & mobile (**Swift** & **JAVA**) application by testing client & reading source code. Identified and reported multiple exploit avenues in web application.

## Education

University of California, San Diego

Chemical Engineering B.S./Computer Science minor

## **SKILLS**

- Proficient Skills: Java; Typescript/Javascript; Python; React; Redux; Node.js; SQL; NoSQL; gRPC; microservices;
   Cassandra; MongoDB; Linux; Git; k8s; Docker; AWS; GCP; Terraform; IaC; VIM; Functional Programming; OpenAPI
- Familiar Skills: Gradle; Airflow; Golang; Play! Framework; PHP; C; C++; Angular; Flask; SASS; Matlab; Swift